<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Go on YING ZHEN LI</title>
    <link>https://www.maxlivinci.com/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Go on YING ZHEN LI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.maxlivinci.com/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing middleware in Golang</title>
      <link>https://www.maxlivinci.com/blog/2019-04-23-writing-middleware-in-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.maxlivinci.com/blog/2019-04-23-writing-middleware-in-golang/</guid>
      <description>When we talk about Middleware in Go, at its simplest, we are really talking about running code before and/or after our handler code in a HTTP request lifecycle. For example, logging middleware might write the incoming request details to a log, then call the handler code, before writing details about the response to the log. One of the cool things about middleware, if implemented correctly, is that these units are extremely flexible, reusable, and sharable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slices from the ground up</title>
      <link>https://www.maxlivinci.com/blog/2019-04-22-slices-from-the-ground-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.maxlivinci.com/blog/2019-04-22-slices-from-the-ground-up/</guid>
      <description>Arrays Arrays in Go have two relevant properties:
 They have a fixed size; [5]int is is distinct from [3]int. They are value types. Consider this example:  package main import &amp;quot;fmt&amp;quot; func main() { var a [5]int b := a b[2] = 7 fmt.Println(a, b) // prints [0 0 0 0 0] [0 0 7 0 0] }  The statement b := a declares a new variable, b, of type [5]int, and copies the contents of a to b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gopher Reading List</title>
      <link>https://www.maxlivinci.com/blog/2019-04-21-gopher-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.maxlivinci.com/blog/2019-04-21-gopher-reading-list/</guid>
      <description>Here is a reading list of blog posts about Go. It aspires to include only the most useful and relevant material that anyone writing Go should eventually read. By definition, the list is a work in progress.
Rather than being comprehensive, the list is a curated selection fixed at 200 entries.
Go is growing fast and so are the number of blog posts about it. If an interested reader knows of a great post not on this list, please open an issue with a link to the post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>