<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rest on YING ZHEN LI</title>
    <link>https://liyingzhen.github.io/tags/rest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rest on YING ZHEN LI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 07:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://liyingzhen.github.io/tags/rest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Response codes</title>
      <link>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-03-17-http-response-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-03-17-http-response-codes/</guid>
      <description>400 Bad Request This response indicates that the request could not be understood by the client due to a malformed request or due to a failure of domain validation (missing data, or an operation that would cause invalid state).
401 Unauthorized This indicates that the request requires user authentication and will include a WWWAuthenticate header containing a challenge applicable to the requested resource. If the user has included the required credentials in the WWW-Authenticate header, then the response should include an error object that may contain relevant diagnostic information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenAPI Specification</title>
      <link>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-01-26-open-api-specification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 18:40:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-01-26-open-api-specification/</guid>
      <description>OpenAPI lets us define RESTful APIs in a standardized manner, and they can be defined without being tied down to any particular programming language or framework being used.
Let&amp;rsquo;s list the general structure of an OpenAPI specification and use it to redefine the Books API described in Chapter 4, The RESTful Web.
If we look at the Books API title, we can define the following elements to describe the API:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP headers</title>
      <link>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-01-12-http-headers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 19:52:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-01-12-http-headers/</guid>
      <description>Authorization - string Authorization is one of the most commonly used request headers, even if you have a public read only API I advise you to ask the user to authorize their requests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>URI path design for REST services</title>
      <link>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-01-12-uri-path-design-for-rest-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2019 19:37:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liyingzhen.github.io/blog/2019-01-12-uri-path-design-for-rest-services/</guid>
      <description>Collections A collection is a directory of resources typically broken by parameters to access an individual document. For example:
GET /cats -&amp;gt; All cats in the collection GET /cats/1 -&amp;gt; Single document for a cat 1  When defining a collection, we should always use a plural noun such as cats or people for the collection name.
Documents A document is a resource pointing to a single object, similar to a row in a database.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>